### **Kyle Sousa**

Phone: 239-770-0763 | Email: <a href="mailto:KyleSousa756@gmail.com">KyleSousa756@gmail.com</a> | Silver Springs, FL 34488 GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/AWSMProdigy">https://github.com/AWSMProdigy</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://awsmprodigy.github.io/Advanced-Portfolio/LinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/kyle-sousa-1a507b156/">https://awsmprodigy.github.io/Advanced-Portfolio/LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kyle-sousa-1a507b156/</a>

#### **Professional Summary:**

Back-end developer with college and bootcamp experience. Has a deep understanding of agile workflow and team cooperation using Git. Capable of creating complex data structures and quickly adapting to any existing back-end solution. Extensive experience creating back-end servers with the skill to implement functionality into the front-end.

#### **Technical Skills**

~90 WPM,

Python Django, NodeJS, ExpressJs, MongoDB, MERN, MySQL, Git, ReactJS, AngularJS, HandlebarsJS, HTML/CSS, GraphQL, RESTful API, Bootstrap, Data structures, Office 365, Linux shell, Javascript

#### **Professional Experience**

Deli Clerk 2019-2020

Fulfill customer orders while providing exemplary customer service

• Communicate with customers and handle complaints

Sales Representative 2018-2019

- Create and maintain relationships with customers
- Sell myself and my products
- Maintain precise scheduling

#### **Education**

UCF Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp 2021

Computer Science Major, University of Florida 2018-present

#### Portfolio/Projects

# $\begin{tabular}{ll} \textbf{Reel Cinema:} & $\underline{https://github.com/AWSMProdigy/Theater-website} \mid \underline{https://intense-lake-77911.herokuapp.com/} \\ \end{tabular}$

- Theater website made for a modern age for theatergoers who enjoy watching movies with their friends but have issues planning on a time and place.
- Uses MySQL and ExpressJs to create a friends list and connect users with the reservations they and their friends have created.
- User creation with authentication

## Dangerous to go Alone: <a href="https://github.com/AWSMProdigy/dangerous-to-go-alone">https://github.com/AWSMProdigy/dangerous-to-go-alone</a> | <a href="https://sheltered-taiga-89649.herokuapp.com/">https://sheltered-taiga-89649.herokuapp.com/</a>

- Website created to help gamers find others with similar interests to play games with
- Allows user to use his library, availability, and other preferences to find suitable candidates to play games with
- Is a MERN stack application, using GraphQL queries to retrieve information from the Mongo database implemented